Now that we have an understanding of some of the fundamental concepts of ROS,
ROS のいくつかの基本コンセプトについて理解できました
we can drive right into the command line where we will create
ここからはコマンドラインについてです
cute little turtle robots with a package called Turtlesim.
Turtlesim というパッケージを使用して 小さくて可愛いカメのロボットを作成します
Like this?
こんな感じ ?
Yeah. Just like this.
ええと うん そんな感じ
OK, but hold on a second.
それはさておき
We should probably stop and explain
ここで一時停止して ロボット工学を使用した可愛くて小さいカメが
what cute little turtles have to do with robotics in the first place.
何をしなければならないか 最初から説明しましょう
Indeed. Well cuteness aside the use of turtles and robotics goes way back to the 1940s.
そうだね可愛いのはともかく カメとロボット工学の使用は 1940 年代まで遡ります
That's right. Early roboticist William Gray Walter
そうです初期のロボット研究家 William Gray Walter は
created some of the first autonomous devices,
最初の自律型デバイスをいくつか生み出しました
turtle robots which he called Elmer and Elsie.
彼はカメのロボットを Elmer と Elsie と呼んでいました
And in the 1960s at MIT,
それから 1960 年代の MIT では
Seymour Papert used turtle robots in robotics education.
Seymour Papert がカメロボをロボット工学の教育に使用しました
Seymour's robots could perform a few basic functions.
Seymour のロボットは いくつかの基本機能を実行できました
They could move forward or backwards by a given distance,
指定された距離を前進したり後退したり
rotate by a given angle,
指定された角度で回転したり
or they could drop the retractable pen on
伸縮ペンをお腹に落とすと
their bellies allowing them to draw as they moved.
自分の動きに応じてそれを引き伸ばしたり
These primitive functions could be triggered simultaneously allowing
初期の機能は 同時に ロボットが複雑なトラジェクトリーに沿って移動したり
the robots to move along complex trajectories and make sophisticated drawings.
洗練された絵を描いたりをトリガーできました
This connection between robots and turtles continues to this very day.
ロボットとカメのこのつながりは 今このときまで続いています
And in your first exercise with ROS,
ROS を使用した最初のエクササイズでは
you'll be launching your own turtle robot and simulation.
自分のカメロボを起動して シミュレーションします